[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning and welcome to
&gt;&gt;  早上好
your Apps and Evolving Network
欢迎来听
Security Standards.
有关应用软件和演化网络安全标准的介绍
My name is Bailey Basile and I'm
我是 Bailey Basile
secure transports engineer at
苹果公司的
Apple.
安全传输工程师
Today, my colleague Chris and I
今天  我的同事 Chris 和我
will be talking to you about the
将会向你介绍网络安全标准的变化
ways that network security
以及这些变化给你
standards change and how that
和你的应用软件
affects you and your apps.
所带来的影响
We know that all of you care as
相信所有用户
much about your users' privacy
都像我们一样
and security as we do.
关心隐私和安全问题
And that's why when you see
这也是为什么
attacks like BEAST, and CRIME,
当你看到像 Beast  Crime 和 Drown 一样的攻击时
and DROWN, you worry about
你会担忧
whether your app is affected.
你的 App 是否受到了影响
Unfortunately, all protocols
不幸的是
age, and as they are in the
所有协议都有使用期限
public more attacks are found
这些协议在公众中使用
over time.
随着时间的推移  它们会受到越来越多的攻击
Even worse, the algorithms upon
更糟的是
which these standards rely have
标准所依赖的算法
a built-in shelf life.
都有自身的保质期
That means that as they age and
这意味着它们会过时
as computers get faster, those
随着电脑的速度越来越快
algorithms become vulnerable to
这些算法在面对诸如冲突
attacks like collisions,
因式分解和暴力这些攻击时
factorization and brute force.
更加的脆弱
When you hear about these scary
这些听起来很可怕的攻击
sounding attacks like a FLAME
像是 Flame Breach
and BREACH, and POODLE.
和 Poodle
Well, maybe poodle doesn't sound
也许 Poodle 听起来
so scary.
并没有那么可怕
When you hear about these scary
当你听到这些可怕的攻击
attacks, you wonder what you can
你就会开始想你能做些什么
do to prevent your app from
来避免你的 App
appearing in the press the next
在下一个严重攻击发生时
time a big attach happens.
受到影响
And that's why today, I'm going
这也是为什么
to be talking about some best
今天我要讲一些
practices that you can follow in
你可以执行的方法
order to ensure that your app is
来保证你的 App
not affected.
不受影响
I'll also talk a little bit
我也会讲到一些
about how Apple helps you by
关于苹果
removing insecure options from
是如何通过把不安全的选项移除我们的运行平台
our platforms.
来帮助你的
Chris will then give you an
Chris 会向你介绍
update on app transport
App 传输安全的更新
security, which is a mechanism
这是一个机制
that you can use in your apps in
你可以用在你的 App 中
order to ensure that best
来保证
practices are enforced.
最优运行
Finally, Chris will be giving
最后
you a talk about Transport Layer
Chris 将会向你介绍
Security, or TLS and an exciting
传输层安全
new evolution in that protocol.
和该协议的重大革新
So, let's dive right into those
现在
best practices.
就让我们开始吧
I'll start at a high level.
我会从高层开始
First, the biggest thing you
首先
have to remember, because as I
你需要记住
said, those protocols age, and
你不能设置
those standards have a built-in
和忘记你 App 的安全性
shelf life, you can't set and
因为我说过所有的协议都有寿命
forget the security of your app.
这些标准都有内置的保质期
You have to go through on a
你必须定期进行检查
regular basis and make sure that
并确认你的 App
your app is up to date.
是最新的
And to know what to change, you
想知道需要改变什么
should be following standards
你必须紧跟标准机构
bodies, academic research and
学术研究
industry best practices.
和行业最佳实践
But the good news for all of
但好消息是
you, is that you are already
你已经这样做了
doing this because you're here
因为你今天
today.
坐在这里
If you are a developer or a
如果你是开发人员
library developer, you may be
或者是库开发者
using a third-party library in
你可能在使用你 App 中的
your app.
第三方库
And those can be very risky.
这对你的应用程序是非常危险的
In particular, if you're
特别是
integrating a third-party
如果你在整合第三方库时
library you have to be sure you
你必须确保第三方库
keep it up to date.
保持最新
A library that you integrated
你三年前集成的库
three years ago is already out
已经过时了
of date and maybe using weakened
而且
security.
可能被削弱了安全性
That means that your users are
这意味着你的用户
not getting the security that
没有得到你想让他们得到的
you want.
安全性
If you're using our APIs, we
如果你在使用我们的 API
help you here.
我们将竭诚为您服务
First, we remove many of the
首先
insecure options from our APIs
我们删除了很多我们的 API 里不安全的选项
so that you aren't affected.
来让你不受影响
We also make available App
我们也提供了 App 传输安全
Transport Security, or ATS, in
即 ATS
order for you to be able to
来使你能够在你的 App 中
enforce those best practices in
执行最佳实践
your app, as long as you are
只要你避免
avoiding ATS exceptions.
ATS 异常
Finally, when those attacks
最后
happen, before those attacks
在这些攻击发生之前
happen you have to remind your
你必须提醒你的客户
clients, investors and managers
投资者和经理人
that it is worth the maintenance
为你的 App 提供维护费
cost to update your app so that
用来对 App 进行更新是十分值得的
when the next attack happens you
因为这样一来
are not scrambling to remediate
当下一次攻击发生时
the problem wasting time and
你不会因为被指责成一个表现欠佳的 App 被扰乱
energy and money as your app
而疯狂补救
appears in the press named as
浪费自身的时间
one of the bad apps.
力气和金钱
So, let's take a look back at
所以
those attacks I was talking
让我们回头看看
about earlier.
我之前提到的那些攻击
I'd like to go through some
我想详细介绍一些最佳的做法
detailed best practices that you
你可以用来
can use to avoid these attacks.
避免这些攻击
Specifically, in the area of
具体来说
encryption, cryptographic
在加密领域中
hashes, public keys, protocols,
有加密杂凑  公钥  协议
and revocation.
和撤销几种方法
So, let's start right off the
所以
bat with encryption.
让我们开始介绍一下加密
Encryption, as all of you know
加密
is a mechanism that you can use
大家都知道
to prevent your users' data from
是一种可以用来防止攻击者
being read by an attacker.
读取你的用户数据的机制
But unfortunately, some of the
但不幸的是
algorithms that we've been using
一些我们长久以来
for encryption for a long time
一直使用的加密算法
are vulnerable to attacks where
在面对攻击时是十分脆弱的
the key material or the plain
因为攻击者可以轻易的
text could be recovered by an
恢复关键数据
attacker.
甚至原文
In particular, RC 4 is
比如
vulnerable to an attack where
RC 4 是非常容易被攻击的
the key is recoverable within as
因为密钥
little as three days.
可以在三天内被恢复出来
Furthermore, the CBC modes of
此外
both Triple-DES and AES are
Triple-DES 和 AES 的 CBC 模式
vulnerable to attacks like BEAST
都是容易受到像 Beast
and Lucky 13 that mean that the
和 Lucky 13 这样的攻击
algorithm is not providing the
这意味着你的算法
same level of security as you
并没有向你的用户提供
want your users to have.
预期中那么高的安全性
We plan to remove both RC 4 and
将来
Triple-DES from TLS across our
我们打算删除我们平台下 TLS 中的
platforms in the future.
RC 4 和 Triple-DES
So, now is the time to upgrade.
所以现在是时候升级了
Instead, you should be using
同时
authenticated encryption
你应该使用认证加密算法
algorithm like AES-GCM or
如 AES-GCM
ChaCha20/Poly1305.
或 ChaCha20 / Poly1305
Those will ensure that you have
这些算法将确保
both the best encryption and can
你不仅有最好的加密
detect when that data has been
并且可以检测到数据
modified.
是否被修改
Speaking of modified data.
说到修改数据
Let's talk now about
我们来讨论一下
cryptographic hashes.
加密杂凑
As you know, cryptographic
众所周知
hashes are a mechanism that
加密杂凑是一种
allows you to detect when the
让你可以监测到数据
input data has been changed.
是否被修改的机制
But unfortunately, some of the
但不幸的是
cryptographic hash algorithms
一些我们一直在使用的
that we've been using are
加密杂凑
vulnerable to what's called a
容易受到所谓的
collision attack.
碰撞攻击
different inputs produce the
是两个不同的输入
exact same output.
产生完全相同的输出
And so, you can't tell when an
所以
attacker has modified the data
你不知道什么时候
because the hashes will be the
攻击者修改了数据
same.
因为得到的哈希值会是相同的
In particular, both MD 5 and
特别是 MD-5
SHA-1 have demonstrated
和 SHA-1
collision attacks.
都已经证实了碰撞攻击
In fact, an MD-5 collision was
事实上
used in the Flame malware in
MD-5 的碰撞
order to bypass platform
是用于火焰恶意软件绕过平台安全
security and gain access to
来获得
users' systems.
访问用户系统的权限
We removed trust in all MD-5
前几年
signed certificates across our
我们删除了我们平台上的
platforms in previous years.
所有 MD-5 证书
SHA-1 just recently had an
SHA-1
attack.
刚刚受到了一次攻击
The Shouted attack was performed
这次攻击
earlier this year, and so this
是在今年早些时候发生的
is the freshest information.
所以这是一个最新的信息
Knowing that the SHA-1 one
知道 SHA-1 的攻击即将来临
attack was imminent, we removed
我们删除了
trust in all SHA-1 signed
使用 WebKit 和 Safari 建立连接时
certificates for TLS servers
所有对于 TLS 服务器
when connecting through WebKit
签署的
and Safari.
SHA-1 证书
And we've seen such an
我们已经看到
improvement in the disk use of
SHA-1 证书中
SHA-1 certificates, that today
磁盘使用的改进
I'm announcing that we're
今天我宣布
removing trust across all TLS
我们要清除
connections for SHA-1 signed
所有 SHA-1 证书中的
certificates.
TLS 连接
I'll talk a little bit more
我会再更多地介绍
about how that affects you and
这将如何影响你
your app later on.
和你的 App
Instead, you should be using any
此外
of the SHA-2 family of hashes in
为了获得最好的安全性
order to get that best security
并避免这些碰撞攻击
and avoid these collision
你应该使用任何一种 SHA-2 系列的
attacks.
哈希算法
Next, I'd like to talk about
接下来
public keys.
我想谈谈公钥
Public keys, as you know, are a
像大家熟知的一样
mechanism that provides an
公钥是一种
identity, a sort of identity for
提供身份的
you.
机制
Such that other people can
因此
verify that something you signed
别人可以验证
was signed by you and not
你签署的东西是你签的
someone else.
而不是其他人签的
And can be used to send you
并可以用来
encrypted data that only you can
给你发送只有你可以用你的私钥解密的
decrypt with your private key.
加密数据
But unfortunately, RSA key sizes
但不幸的是
smaller than 1024 bits are
RSA 密钥大小小于 1024 位
vulnerable to factorization
所以对于因式分解类的攻击来说
attacks.
是非常脆弱的
In particular, a 768-bit RSA key
特别是
was factored back in 2009 and
一个 768 位的 RSA 密钥
that's why we removed trust from
在 2009 年就被因式分解了
any certificates using key sizes
这就是为什么我们在 2016 年春季的时候
smaller than 1024 bit RSA back
就移除了
in the spring of 2016.
所有使用小于 1024 位 RSA 的证书
But the reality is even 1024 bit
但现实是
RSA key sizes are not good
哪怕 1024 位的 RSA 密钥
enough.
都不是足够完美的
And we expect that an attack on
并且我们认为马上
a 1024 bit RSA key is imminent.
就会有一次针对 1024 位 RSA 密钥的攻击
And that's why today I'm
所以这意味着
announcing that we're removing
我们将会移除
trust from certificates using
所有
key sizes smaller than 2048 bits
TLS 服务器连接中的
across all TLS connections to
小于 2048 位密钥尺寸的
servers.
证书
In order to avoid these removals
为了避免这些清除
and ensure that you have best
并确保你有最好的安全保障
security, you should be using
你应该
RSA key sizes greater than or
使用密钥大小大于
equal to 2048 bits, or any of
或等于 2048 位的RSA密钥
the elliptic curves that are
或任何我们平台信任的
trusted on our platforms.
椭圆曲线
Next, I'd like to spend some
接下来
time talking about protocols.
我想花一些时间谈论协议
Protocols, as you know, are the
众所周知
mechanism that you actually use
协议是
to talk to servers.
与服务器交流时使用的机制
They are interoperable, which
它们是能共同操作的
means that you don't have to
这意味着
worry whether the server you're
你不必担心
talking to across the world
你所交流的服务器
supports the protocol you're
是否支持
using.
你使用的协议
Unfortunately, some of these
不幸的是
protocols are weak or provide no
其中一些协议
security in particular.
比较薄弱或不提供安全性
If you are using http all of
如果你使用 http
your users' data is being
那么
transmitted in the clear.
你所有的用户数据都会被透明地传输
That means that anyone listening
这意味着
in knows exactly that data.
任何人都可以知道这些数据
But some of the older TLS
但是
versions, like SSL Version 3,
一些较旧的 TLS 版本
TLS 1.0, and TLS 1.1 are also
如 SSL Version 3 TLS 1.0 和 TLS 1.1
vulnerable to numerous attacks.
也是容易受到众多攻击的
And so, you should be avoiding
所以
these when you configure your
当你配置你的服务器时
servers.
应该避免这些
We removed the use of SSL
在 2015 年秋天
Version 3 back in fall of 2015.
我们删除了 SSLVersion 3
So, you've been protected on
所以
that count for a while.
你暂时是受到保护的
Instead, you should be using
并且
HTTPS, that is HTTP over TLS,
你应该使用
with TLS 1.2.
HTTPS 和 TLS 1.2
TLS 1.2 is the current best
TLS 1.2
standard available for TLS
是目前可用于 TLS 安全的
security.
最好的标准
But I'm pleased to announce
但我很高兴地宣布
today that we're adding support
今天
for the draft specification of
我们正在增加
TLS 1.3.
对于 TLS 1.3 草案规范的支持
Chris will be talking more about
Chris 一会将会更多地
that a little bit later.
谈论这方面的信息
Finally, I'd like to talk about
最后
revocation.
我想谈谈撤销
Revocation is the mechanism that
撤销
clients use to verify the
是一种客户用来
certificate and determine
验证证书
whether that certificate should
并确定
be trusted in the event that a
当证书处理不当
certificate is mishandled or
或过期时
missed issued.
该证书是否应该被信任的机制
And of course, the worst thing
当然
you can do in the area of
最糟糕的是
revocation is not check it.
你可以不检查就撤销
Unfortunately, our platforms do
不幸的是
not check revocation by default
目前
currently and I'll explain why
我们的平台默认情况下不检查撤销
later.
我之后会解释这是为什么
That is, unless of course you
也就是说
are using OCSP Stapling.
除非你正在使用 OCSP Stapling
OCSP being the Online
OCSP 是
Certificate Status Protocol.
在线证书状态协议
If your servers are using OCSP
如果
Stapling, your certificates are
你的服务器正在使用 OCSP Stapling
always being checked for
你的证书就会
revocation.
总是被检查撤销
So, let's drill down into how
所以
OCSP and OCSP Stapling work.
让我们深入了解一下 OCSP 和
First, as usual, a server
OCSP Stapling 工作机制 首先
requests a certificate from a
像往常一样
trusted third-party called a
服务器从可信的
certificate authority.
被称为证书颁发机构的第三方请求证书
The server then uses that
然后
certificate to identify itself
服务器使用这个证书
to clients connecting to it.
来让连接到它的客户端识别自己
The client, in order to verify
客户端
that identity, then requests
为了验证那个身份
information as to the status of
从证书颁发机构
that certificate from the
请求
certificate authority.
关于该证书状态的信息
The certificate authority
认证机构
replies back with a signed
回复一条
message indicating the status of
已认证的消息
the certificate that the client
来表明
is looking at.
客户端所查找的证书的状态
The client verifies that
客户端
response and then uses that
确定该回应后
status to determine whether to
使用返回的证书状态
continue the connection to the
来判断是否
server.
要继续连接服务器
But unfortunately, OCSP has some
但不幸的是
drawbacks.
OCSP 有一些缺点
As you can see from that
从之前的介绍
previous description It requires
你可以看出
an additional network connection
对于每一个
for every connection to the
对服务器的连接
server.
它都需要一个额外的网络连接
That means that your connections
这意味着
in your apps appear slower and
你的 App 内部连接会很慢
none of us want that.
这是我们不想看到的
Furthermore, OCSP is performed
此外
in the clear.
OCSP 是完全透明的执行的
That means that all of the
这意味着
traffic indicating which
所有的传输
certificate the client wants
都表明了用户想要查询哪一个证书
checked is visible to anybody
这对于任何人
watching.
都是透明的
And the reason that OCSP is
OCSP
performed in the clear is that
之所以透明化的原因是
it you would need it to
你需要它
establish a secure connection.
来建立安全的连接
So, if you had to establish a
所以
secure connection to get OCSP,
如果你需要建立一个安全连接
you might end up in a circular
来实现 OCSP
problem.
你将会陷入一个死循环
That's why OCSP is a huge
这就是为什么
compromise of your users'
OCSP 是对用户隐私的
privacy.
巨大牺牲
Since all that information is in
因为
the clear.
所有的信息都是透明化的
Anyone who is listening can and
任何正在监听的人
find out what servers that
都可以找出
client is connecting to.
客户端在试图连接哪一个服务器
Furthermore, that third-party
此外
certificate authority can
该第三方证书颁发机构
aggregate data as to which IP
可以汇总
address is which clients are
关于哪个客户端试图连接哪个服务器
talking to which servers and
向哪个 IP 地址传输等这些信息
sell that to anybody they want.
并将这些信息售卖给别人
So, that's very bad.
这是非常糟糕的
These 2 drawbacks are the reason
这两个缺点的原因
that we do not have OCSP enabled
是
by default.
我们没有默认启用 OCSP
And if you wanted to enable OCSP
如果你想在你的 App 中
in your app you would have to
启用 OCSP
integrate additional APIs.
你将不得不集成额外的 API
So, next I want to talk about
所以
OCSP Stapling, which is a
接下来我想谈谈 OCSP Stapling
dramatic improvement on OCSP and
这是一个 OCSP 的
an evolution in the protocol
巨大改进
that removes many of the
并且是协议的一个重大革新
drawbacks of OCSP.
因为它删掉了 OCSP 的很多缺点
As before, the server gets a
像以前一样
certificate from the certificate
服务器从证书颁发机构
authority.
得到一个证书
But before sending that
但
certificate to a client, the
在发送证书给客户端之前
server requests the OCSP
服务器
response from the certificate
请求从证书颁发机构的
authority.
OCSP 回复
And when it gets that signed
当传回已认证的回复后
response back, the server
服务器
verifies it and then sends it
会对该回复进行验证
along with the certificate to
然后再将该回复
the client.
与证书一起传回给客户端
The client can then verify both
客户端
the certificate and the
便能同时
revocation status
验证证书
simultaneously.
和撤销状态
So, this is a huge win, both in
所以
terms of performance, because
这是一个巨大的改进
you don't need that additional
在性能方面
network connection on your
你不必再在你的客户端上
client.
建立额外的网络连接
And in terms of privacy, because
在隐私方面
the client doesn't have to
客户端
connect to a third party to find
不必连接到第三方
out about the revocation status.
来查找撤销状态
But even OCSP Stapling has some
但是
drawbacks.
即使是 OCSP Stapling 也有一些缺点
We've noted that despite
我们注意到
encouraging all of you to adopt
尽管鼓励大家
it on your servers, that
在自己的服务器上采用该机制
adoption has been slow.
这个采用的过程都很缓慢
We are aware that enabling OCSP
我们知道
in some of the open source
在一些开源服务器中
server implementations does have
启用 OCSP
drawbacks.
会有一些缺点
But we, nonetheless, encourage
但是
you to fix those issues and to
我们还是鼓励你
adopt OCSP in order to improve
去解决这些问题
the security and the speed of
并且采用 OCSP
your app.
来提高你 App 的安全性和速度
But the worst thing about OCSP
但是
is that it actually doesn't
OCSP 最糟糕的事情是
protect users against malicious
它实际上
servers.
并没有保护用户免受恶意服务器的攻击
In particular, the malicious
特别是
server just need omit the
恶意服务器
stapled OCSP response and the
只需要省略 OCSP 响应
client will never know that that
客户端
malicious server has a revoked
就永远都不会知道恶意服务器的证书
certificate.
已经被撤销
That's why I'm pleased to
今天
announce to you today that we
我很高兴的向大家宣布
are enhancing revocation across
我们正在加强
all of our platforms.
我们所有平台的
And it starts with us.
撤销机制
First, we gather information
首先
from certificate transparency
我们从证书透明度日志
logs.
收集信息
Certificate transparency logs or
证书透明度日志
CT logs contain cryptographic
包含
proofs of the existence of a
一个证书的
certificate.
加密证明
You can find out more about CT
你可以通过
and how it works and how you can
看去年的“安全新特性”
use it to enhance the security
来得到更多
of your app by watching last
关于证书透明度的信息
year's "What's New in Security"
以及它是怎样工作的
session.
你要如何使用它来提高你 App 的安全性
We use the information from the
我们使用
certificate transparency logs to
从证书透明度日志上
find out about all of the
得到的信息
certificates that are trusted on
来找到所有
our platforms.
我们平台所信任的证书
And if you want to help us
如果
gather information about your
你想帮助我们
certificates in your apps and
搜集有关你的 App
your servers, you should verify
和服务器的证书信息
that your certificates are
你需要验证你的证书是否
logged to a CT log.
已经记录在了证书透明度日志中
Many CA's will do this for you
许多 CA 将为你做这件事
so you just need check.
所以你只需要检查
With that information, we now
有了这些信息
know all of the certificate
我们就能知道
authorities that are trusted on
所有被我们平台所信任的
our platforms.
证书颁发机构
And from that information we can
并且
request all of the revocation
通过这些信息
information from those
我们可以从证书颁发机构
certificate authorities.
请求所有的撤销信息
We then gather all of that
然后
revocation information back.
我们收集所有这些撤销信息
We aggregate it into a single
我们把这些撤销信息
efficient bundle, and then make
都聚集在一起
it available to all of our
我们的所有客户端
clients.
都可以使用这些信息
Those clients check in
那些客户
periodically with us to get that
定期登记
bundled revocation information,
来获取撤销信息
and use that latest status
并且
revocation information when
当他们在检查
checking server certificates
他们所用的服务器证书时
that they are using.
使用这些最新的撤销信息
If the client hits a certificate
如果客户端点击
that is listed there, the client
一个在撤销列表中的证书
will then perform OCSP.
客户端就会运行 OCSP
Unless of course your app is
除非
using OCSP Stapling.
你的 App 在使用 OCSP Stapling
The client uses this to verify
客户端
that the certificate really is
使用这种方法来
revoked.
验证证书真的已经被撤销
So, we think this is a dramatic
所以
improvement on the existing
我们说
state of revocation on our
对于当年我们平台的撤销状态
platforms.
这是一个巨大的进步
It has a dramatic improvement in
在隐私妥协领域
the privacy compromise area.
也有一个重大的改进
The bundle that we provide of
我们所提供的
revocation information is the
撤销信息
same across all of our clients
对于我们所有的客户端
and all of our platforms.
和所有的平台都是相同的
So, we never know which clients
所以
are connecting to which servers.
我们永远不会知道是哪个客户端
Furthermore, only certificates
连接到了哪个服务器 此外
that are in that list require
只有在那个列表中的证书
the additional OCSP connection.
才需要额外的 OCSP 连接
So, only the limited set of
所以
certificates there risk that
如果你的服务器
additional privacy compromise if
没有用 OCSP Stapling
your servers are not using OCSP
只有小部分证书
Stapling.
将面临额外隐私妥协的危险
Another huge advantage is that
另一个巨大的优势
the information is automatically
是
updated.
信息是自动更新的
That means that the client
这意味着
always have that freshest
当客户端
revocation information available
在建立连接时
to them when making all of their
他们总能获得
connections and this means that
最新的撤销信息
you also get this for free.
并且这一切都是免费的
You don't need to make a single
你不需要
API call to get this best
建立一个单独的 API
practice security and faster
来获得这种最高的安全性
connections.
和更快的连接速度
So, I've covered a lot of ground
在之前的二十分钟
in the last 20 minutes and I'd
我已经讲了大部分的内容
like to recall what we talked
接下来
about.
我想对这些内容进行一下回顾
First we talked about encryption
首先
and using authenticated
我们讨论了加密
encryption ciphers in your
和在你的服务器或 App 中使用
servers and your apps.
认证的加密密码
We talked about hashes and how
我们讨论了哈希算法
to avoid collision attacks.
以及如何避免碰撞攻击
We talked about public keys and
我们谈论了公钥
using strong public keys that
和使用强大的
are not subject to
不受因式分解影响的
factorization.
公钥
We also talked about protocols
我们还谈及了协议
and using the latest protocols
以及使用最新的协议
like TLS 1.2 and HTTPS to secure
如 TLS 1.2 和 HTTPS
your apps.
来保护你的 App
Finally, we talked about
最后
revocation and how you can
我们谈了一下撤销
improve the security of your app
及如何通过
by using revocation and OCSP
在服务器上使用撤销
Stapling on your servers, and
来提高你的 App 的安全性
the ways in which we've helped
及我们研究出的
you with a brand-new revocation
可以帮助到你的
mechanism.
全新的撤销机制
Now, I promise you that I'd talk
现在
a little bit more about those
我要讲一下
trust removals that I announced
我之前所提到的
earlier.
移除一些不安全选项
Let's go back and recall what
我们先来回忆一下刚才提到的
those trust removals were.
移除的内容都是什么
First, I announced that we would
首先
be removing trust in any SHA-1
我提到说
signed certificate for
我们会在所有我们的平台中
connections to TLS servers
移除所有对 TLS 服务器连接的
across all of our platforms.
SHA-1 的证书
I also announced that we would
我还说过
be removing trust in
我们将会移除所有
certificates using key sizes
使用密钥尺寸小于 2048 位 RSA 的证书
smaller than 2048 bit RSA, also
包括
in all TLS connections to
对服务器的所有
servers.
TLS 连接
If you are connecting to a
如果
server using TLS that has one of
你用来连接到服务器的 TLS
these weak certificates, your
包含
app will fail to make that
以上所提到的安全性较低的证书
connection on macOS High Sierra
你的 App 会无法在
and iOS 11, and watchOS 4 and
macOS High Sierra iOS 11 watchOS 4
tvOS 11.
和 Apple tvOS 11上 建立连接
Let's back up and remind
让我们接下来讨论一下
ourselves what certificates this
基于我刚才的讲解
trust removal does not affect
哪些证书是在信任移除中
based on my description.
没有受到影响的
First, this does not affect root
首先
certificates.
根证书并没有受到影响
In particular, root certificates
因为
are not subject to the type of
根证书不受到
collision attacks that we are
我们所担忧的
worried about with the SHA-1.
SHA-1 中的碰撞攻击的影响
Also, we already removed all
并且
roots certificates using key
在 2015 年秋季
sizes smaller than 2048 bits
我们就已经移除了
back in fall of 2015.
所有使用的密钥尺寸小于 2048 位的根证书
So, you've been protected there
所以
for awhile.
你目前是受到保护的
These trust removals also do not
这些信任
affect enterprise distributed
也并没有影响到
certificates through mobile
移除移动设备管理中的
device management or MDM.
企业分布式证书
It also doesn't affect user
它也没有影响到
installed certificates through
邮件 Safari 和钥匙串访问中的
mail, Safari or keychain access.
用户安装证书
Finally, it also doesn't affect
最后
client certificates when used
它也不影响在 TLS 中
with mutual authentication in
使用相互认证的
TLS.
客户端证书
It's not that we're not worried
这并不是说
about attacks on the
我们不担心对于证书的攻击
certificates, we are.
事实上，我们非常担忧
But we know that it takes time
但是我们知道
for enterprises and users to
企业和用户
update all of their certificates
需要花费一些时间
and their infrastructures to use
来更新他们的证书
the latest algorithms.
以及更新他们的基础设施以便使用最新的算法
And so, we're giving them just a
所以
little bit more time.
我们为他们预留了一些时间
removing trust in those
我们将会晚一些
certificates later on.
再移除那些证书
So now is the time to start
所以
updating, not then.
现在是时候开始更新的工作了
Now, you're probably wondering
你也许会好奇说
what this looks like.
移除的证书到底看起来是什么样子的
Because if it's affecting your
因为如果它们会影响到你的App
app, you need to know.
你是应该做一些了解的
If you are in Safari, you see an
如果你使用 Safari
error dialog that looks
你会看到一个像这样的
something like this.
错误对话框
And if we drill into the
如果
certificate pane, we see that
我们深入看一下证书窗格
there's a specific error message
我们就会发现
for these removed weak
对于这些移除的证书
certificates.
都会有一个具体的错误信息
And that's how you will know if
这样
you're connecting to such a
你就会知道
certificate.
你是否连接到了一个这样的证书
Now, many of you are app
你们中的很多人
developers and so you care more
都是 App 开发人员
about what you're going to see
所以
in the logs.
你们会更加关心你将会在日志中看到些什么
Because you may never connect to
因为你可能永远不会通过 Safari
this server through Safari.
来连接到这个服务器
If you're looking in the logs,
如果你正在查看日志
you're going to see an invalid
你会在你的 URL 会话
searching or -9807 SSL error in
或者 URL 连接中
your URL session or URL
看到无效搜索
connection.
或者 -9807 SSL 错误信息
There's only one thing that you
你只能通过一个方法
can do in order to fix this
来修复这个问题
problem and that is to have your
就是让你的服务器管理员
server administrators upgrade
升级他们的服务器
their servers to use new
以使用
certificates.
新的证书
The good news is that all
好消息是
certificate authorities trusted
所有我们平台
on our platforms only issue
所信任的证书颁发机构
certificates that are not
都不受到
subject to these removals and
这些证书移除的影响
you can find a list of all of
并且
the root certificates that are
你可以从这个连接上
trusted on our platforms at this
找到所有我们平台所信任的
link.
根证书列表
So, we've covered quite a bit
我们现在的讲解
more ground now and I think I at
又更多地覆盖了一些内容
least am wondering what should I
现在当我回到我的办公室
do when I go back to my office.
至少我会开始想我应该做些什么
How can I ensure that I have
我应该怎样才能保证
best security.
我有最好的安全措施
And the very first thing you
所以
should do is check your
你需要做的第一件事
implementations, libraries and
就是依据那些我所提到的
servers against those best
最好的安全措施
practices that I've listed.
来检查你的执行 库和服务器
We even have that handy chart
我们甚至有一些
that you can use to ensure that
很方便的图表
you have those good algorithms.
你可以使用它们来确保你使用了
If you're a server developer you
最好的算法 如果
might actually have quite a bit
你是一个服务器开发人员
of work to do in order to ensure
你需要做一些工作
you have the best security for
来确保你为你所有的客户端
all of your clients.
提供了最好的安全性
You should go through and
你需要浏览
replace any SHA-1 or weak RSA
并替换
key certificates so that your
所有 SHA-1
clients will not see failures on
或者薄弱的 RSA 密钥证书
our platforms.
来保证你的客户不会在我们的平台运行失败
And if you haven't already, you
此外
should upgrade your servers to
你应该将你的服务器升级至 TLS 1.2
TLS 1.2 and one of those
并且
authenticated encryption ciphers
使用我之前所提到的
that I listed earlier.
任何一种权威的加密密码
You should allow the client to
你应该
determine what order to use
让用户来决定这些密码的顺序
those ciphers because the
因为
clients may be optimizing to use
对于同等安全性的密码
the best and fastest cipher as
用户倾向于
opposed to one of the slower
使用那些
equally secure ciphers.
更好更快的密码
If you haven't already should
同时
also enable OCSP Stapling so
你还需要启用 OCSP Stapling
that you can be sure that all of
以确认
your clients always have up to
你所有的客户端
date revocation information and
都实时得到
don't have to make privacy
最新的撤销信息
compromising additional network
并且保证你的客户
connections.
不需要建立额外的隐私妥协网络连接
Finally, in order to help us
最后
with our new revocation
为了帮助我们建立
mechanism you should check that
我们新的撤销机制
your certificates are being logs
我们需要你检查你的证书
to a certificate transparency
是否已经记录在了
log.
证书透明度日志中
Now many of you are probably app
你们中的很多人
developers.
是 App 开发人员
And the good news for you is
你们来说好消息是
that you have only one job.
你们只需要做一个工作
Our platform has made it easy to
我们平台易于
adopt best practices and all you
让你们采用最佳实践
have to do is avoid ATS
并且你们要做的
exceptions.
只是避免使用例外的 ATS
If you are using an ATS
如果
exception.
你正在使用一个例外的 ATS
You are saying that connection
你的连接
should have weaker security than
就不能达到我们平台
our platform can enforce.
所想要实现的安全级别
So, now Chris is going to talk
所以
to you about app transport
现在 Chris 将会向你介绍更多的
security a little bit more and
一些关于 App 传输安全的内容
give you an update on the
并且
current status.
向你介绍当前的最新动态
Chris.
Chris
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Bailey.
&gt;&gt;  谢谢 Bailey
Now, continuing along this
现在
thread of best practices, I want
我想更深入地
to dive a little bit deeper into
探讨一下
ATS.
ATS
ATS for those that aren't
ATS 其实就是
familiar is a feature we
我们在 iOS 9 中
released in iOS 9 and
所添加的一个功能
[inaudible] aimed at increasing
旨在
the security and privacy of your
提高用户数据的
customers' data.
安全性和隐私性
ATS ensures that most of the
ATS 确保大部分
application data sent over the
通过网络发送的
network is encrypted and
应用数据
protected by default.
都被默认加密和保护
Basically, this means moving
这意味着
away from insecure and legacy
我们从不安全的 HTTP
HTP toward HTTPS.
转变成了 HTTPS
And that means a couple things,
这也意味着一些事情
the first of which is to use the
首先
latest standardized version TLS,
意味着要使用最新标准版本的 TLS
version 1.2.
即 版本 1.2
This has been updated and
这些
amended over the years to take
都在这几年间
into account some of the attacks
进行了不断地更新和维护
that Bailey eluded to earlier.
因为我们考虑了之前 Bailey 所提及的那些攻击
It also means using strong
这也意味着
cryptography.
使用更强力的加密
That means using block cyphers
这意味着
like AES and hash functions from
使用块加密
the SHA-2 family.
像SHA-2种类中的 AES 算法和哈希函数
Importantly, it also means using
更重要的是
key exchange algorithms that
它也意味着
provide forward secrecy.
使用密钥交换算法来提供保密性
And this is an increasingly
在当今社会
important property in today's
你的应用数据
day where the content of your
在网络上传输时
application's data as
可以保持安全
transmitted over the network are
甚至
kept save, even in the event
在服务器长时间有效的私钥受到威胁的时候
that the long-term private key
应用数据也能保持安全
of a server is compromised.
这变得越来越重要
Now, we live in a world where
现如今
not all TL servers are equal,
我们生活的世界中
and moreover, not all TLS
不是所有的传输层服务器都是相同的
servers use the same version or
也不是所有的传输层服务器
configuration.
都是相同的版本和配置
For example, you might have to
举例来说
connect to an add server that
你可能需要连接一个
doesn't even support HTTPS.
根本不支持 HTTPS 的服务器
So, what do you do?
这时候你该怎么办
This is where exceptions come
这
in.
就是一个例外
Exceptions allow your app to opt
这种例外的情况
out of ATS enforcement for
在特定领域
particular domains, or globally
或者全球领域
across your application.
允许你的 App 退出 ATS
Exceptions are intended to be
例外情况
temporary to help you maintain
可以在服务器
functionality while servers
向更新的 TLS 配置更新时
upgrade to more modern TLS
暂时性的
configurations.
帮你保持功能
Last year, we announced plans to
去年
start requiring justification
我们提出针对 App store 的例外情况
for exceptions in the app store.
需要提供理由这一方案
And since then, we've heard that
自那开始
the exceptions we had available
我们发现
to you did not adequately meet
我们当前所有可用的例外情况
all of your use cases.
并没有完全解决你们所有的情况
And since universal ATS adoption
但是
remains our primary goal, we've
因为全球化的 ATS 使用
taken that time to update the
一直是我们的目标
exceptions that we have
我们一直在花时间
available to you to meet and
更新我们所有的例外情况
satisfy these use cases.
以便可以满足所有的情况
And I want to dive into some
所以
recent ones that were added in
现在我想谈论一些
the past.
我们最近刚刚添加的例外情况
Specifically, we've gone beyond
具体来说
just acceptance for WebKit
我们已经不再
content.
仅仅接受 WebKit 的内容
There are exceptions now to
现在
ensure that if you are streaming
有一些例外情况
data through the AVFoundation
可以确保说你在通过 AVFoundation
framework that happens to be
来进行数据流传输时
encrypted at rest, you can opt
你可以
out of ATS for that particular
对于这些特定的数据
data.
不使用 ATS
We also have exceptions to
我们也有一些例外情况
support opting out of ATS for
来支持任意的
arbitrary WebView request and
WebView 请求
opting out of ATS for local
不使用 ATS
network connections.
或者让本地网络连接不使用 ATS
Here, local network connections
这里所说的
is just a connection made to a
本地网络连接
raw IP address, or a server with
只是一个到原始 IP 地址的连接
an unqualified domain name.
或者到一个拥有不受限域名的服务器的连接
I want to be clear, even though
我还想做一点说明
it may not be necessary for the
尽管说
security and privacy of your
不使用 ATS
data to opt out of ATS, because
对于你数据的安全性和隐私性来说不是必须的
you have otherwise encrypted
因为
your data before transmitting
你还会在传输你的数据前进行加密
it.
但是
We still believe that the right
我们仍然觉得
and proper thing to do is to use
使用 TLS 来保护你的数据传输
TLS to protect your data in
是最为正确
transit.
和合适的
That means as app developers,
就像
and as Bailey already mentioned,
Bailey 之前提到的一样
your goal should be to minimize
你需要在你的能力范围内
or remove exceptions where at
尽可能地
all possible, if it is within
减小甚至消除
your power to do so.
所有的例外情况
I also want to point out a
我还想介绍一下
recent key that was added to
我们最近
support certificate
为了支持证书透明度
transparency.
所添加的密钥
If you want a particular server
如果
to opt into or participate in
你想要让一个特定的服务器
certificate transparency to help
加入证书透明度
protect your apps, and users'
来帮助你保护你的 App
apps against certificate
和用户的 App
[inaudible] attacks, you can
免受证书攻击
specify for a particular domain
你可以指定一个特定的域
whether or not you want that
不管你是否想要该服务器
server to participate in CT.
加入证书透明度
Now, we remain committed to ATS.
当下  我们仍然致力于 ATS
And in the past year we've
在过去几年
continued upgrading the services
我们不断升级
that we make available to you as
我们可以为开发者所提供的服务
developers, to make sure that
以此保证
they are ATS compliant.
这些服务都支持 ATS
All the services you see here
所有你现在在这里看到的服务
are fully ATS compliant, meaning
都是支持 ATS 的
that your apps will not have to
这意味着
specify and exceptions when
你的 App
talking to them.
不会遇到例外情况
You get best practice network
我们的最终目标是
security out of the box, which
你得到最佳的
is the ultimate goal.
网络安全
Now, also in this past year, we
在过去的几年中
kept an eye on the app store to
我们一直监测
track and see how ATS adoption
App Store
is going.
来追踪 ATS 使用的进展
We see adoption increasing.
我们看到
We've also been seeing the
越来越多的人
number of exceptions increasing.
使用 ATS
Which means that there's still
我们也看到有更多的例外情况出现
more work to be done.
这也意味着我们要做的工作还有很多
If you are an app developer,
如果你是一个 App 开发人员
continue to be vigilant and
请继续保持警觉
remove, or minimize your reliant
并且尽可能减小
on exceptions.
甚至消除你对于例外情况的依赖
If you are a server operator or
如果你是一个服务器运行人员
owner, please continue upgrading
或者服务器的拥有者
your server configurations to
请继续更新你的服务器配置
support 1.2 and more modern
以支持 1.2 版本
versions of TLS.
甚至更新版本的 TLS
Now, speaking of TLS, I want to
既然提及 TLS
give you a brief glimpse into
我想向你们进行一个简短的
the future of this critical
有关这种安全协议未来发展方向的
security protocol.
介绍
For those of you who don't know,
TLS 如今
TLS is quickly becoming the
已经成为了
[inaudible] of the internet.
互联网的重要组成部分
More and more of your traffic is
当下
protected on the wire thanks to
越来越多的数据传输
TLS, today.
因为 TLS 而受到了保护
However, not all traffic is
然而
protected the same.
并不是所有的传输都受到了同等的保护
This protocol has been with us
这个协议
for many, many years and there
已经存在了很多很多年
are many different
并且
implementations and
对于服务器来说
configurations of servers out
有很多不同的实现和配置
there supporting a wide variety
支持很多不同的
of TLS versions.
TLS 版本
And over time the protocol has
此协议
been patched and amended to
也在不断地被修缮
generally address some of the
为了应对之前 Bailey 所提到的
attacks that Bailey eluded to
那些攻击
earlier and just to fix up
或完善
general deficiency in the
协议中的
protocol.
一些不足
In recent years, the internet
最近几年
community has taken it upon
互联网协会认为
themselves and deemed it
有必要
necessary to start working on
开始这个协议
the next version of this
下一个版本的工作
critical protocol.
即 TLS 1.3
TLS 1.3. And in the spirit of
本着为大家提供最优质服务的原则
best practices, we are closely
我们正在密切关注这项工作的开展
tracking this work to ensure
以保证
that we are ready to adopt it
我们随时准备好采用这种新的版本
and help you adopt it when it
并且在当它成为一个新的标准时
becomes a standard.
可以及时帮助大家更新这种标准
TLS 1.3 is truly best practice
从设计方面来看
by design.
TLS 1.3 是真正的最优选择
All of the features, the
遵从
majority of the features that
ATS 配置的
are in ATS compliance
大部分的功能
configurations are simply part
都是核心标准的
of the core standard.
一部分
That means legacy cryptographic
这意味着
cipher suites, hash functions,
旧密码  密码套件  哈希函数
and key exchange algorithms are
以及密钥交换算法
simply not allowed.
都是不被允许的
Not that you shouldn't use them,
不是说你不能使用它们
they're just not there to begin
只是说
with.
他们在这里使用不合适
That means the specification is
这意味着
overall much simpler.
规格更加的简单
Which means that it's easier to
意味着更容易实现
implement, easier to reason
更容易理解
about, and most importantly
并且
easier to test.
更容易测试
And this gives us greater
这也让我们更加相信
confidence that the
这个版本的实现
implementation is free, or at
可以让 TLS 库
least has very few problems that
更少的
have plagued TLS libraries in
甚至免于之前的
the past.
一些问题
As a result of this simplicity,
这种简单性
it also has improved network
还能带来的一大优势是
efficiency.
它可以提高网络效率
And let me show you what I mean
让我来向大家讲解
by that.
这具体是什么意思
Let's walk through a typical
让我们回顾一下
handshake in TLS 1.2 and 1.3 to
通过 TLS 1.2 和 TLS 1.3握手
establish a connection to a
来跟服务器
server.
建立连接
We start with a TCP connection,
我们从 TCP 连接开始
which requires one round trip
TCP 连接
between the client and the
需要客户端与服务器之间
server.
完成一个往返过程
Next step you start your TLS
下一步
handshake, where the client and
你建立你的 TLS 握手
server exchange some hellos and
客户端和服务器
some initial centrifugation
可以借此交换问好信息
information needed to proceed
或者之后连接所需要的
with the rest of the connection.
初步配置信息
In TLS 1.3, they actually start
在 TLS 1.3 中
also negotiating key material
除了之前所说之外
used to encrypt the rest of the
它还会处理这一阶段中
traffic sent over that section,
用于之后加密的材料
which means that in the next
这意味着
round, the client can start
在下一次传输时
sending application data.
客户端可以传输应用数据
In 1.2, the client and server
而在 1.2 中
are still negotiating key
客户端和服务器
material, which means that
是在第二次传输中处理加密材料的
requires one more round trip to
这意味着
establish this session and start
1.2 比 1.3 多需要一些时间
sending data.
来开始数据传输
Now, this may not seem like a
也许这听起来没什么
lot, but let me put it in
但是
perspective for you.
让我从你的视角来看待一下这个问题
We collect data from a wide
我们从各种各样的设备和网络中
variety of devices on different
搜集数据
networks, both carrier, cellular
如运营商，蜂窝网络
and wi-fi around the world.
和无线网络
And our data suggests that at
我们的数据表明
least 10% of cellular
至少百分之十的蜂窝网络连接
connections, or at least 10% of
或者说
TLS connections on cellular
至少蜂窝网络中
networks, rather, require at
百分之十的 TLS 连接
least 800 milliseconds to
都至少需要 800 毫秒
complete.
来建立
And 10% of TLS connections on
无线网络中
wi-fi networks take 500
百分之十的 TLS 连接
milliseconds to complete.
需要 500 毫秒来建立
TLS 1.3 would effectively shave
TLS 1.3
1/3 of that time off, which is a
将会缩减三分之一的时间
huge win in mobile world.
这意味着移动领域的一个巨大的成功
Now, TLS 1.3 is still very much
现在
a work in progress.
TLS 1.3 还只是一个正在发展中的项目
And that's why ATS compliance is
这也是为什么 ATS
still focused on getting you to
主要致力于让你们使用 1.2
1.2, and ensuring that you're
以确保
using the latest proper standard
你们使用最合适的
of the protocol.
最新的协议标准
However, if you want to
但是
experiment with TLS 1.3 to
如果你想要对于 TLS 1.3
prepare yourself for this
进行测试
protocol, I'm pleased to
并使你自己对这个协议有所准备
announce that we can now allow
那么我很高兴地告诉大家
you to do that.
我们允许大家进行这种操作
It is not on by default in any
这在我们任何系统中
of our systems.
都不是默认设置
However, if you opt into the
但是
seed and want to start
如果你想要进行这种尝试
experimenting with it, you can
你可以在 iOS 上安装协议子集
install a profile on iOS, or
或者
enable system wide TLS 1.3 on
用简单地写入默认设置
macOS with the simple defaults
来使 TLS 1.3
write.
在 macOS 系统中可用
And you would do this to prime
当明年
your application and your
这个协议趋于标准化的时候
network as the protocol marches
你可以通过这些方法
toward standardization in the
来让你的 App
next year.
和网络提前做好准备
And in the meantime, we're
与此同时
paying our due diligence and
我们花费了大量的时间和精力
working with third parties and
跟第三方
with our enterprise partners to
和我们的企业伙伴一起工作
ensure their apps and their
致力于
networks are ready for the
确保他们的 App
adoption of the protocol as
和网络
well.
都为这个协议做好准备
Now, I want to take a step back
现在
and come full circle with
我想整体总结一下
everything Bailey and I talked
今天我和 Bailey
about today.
一起讲到的内容
One of our primary objectives is
我们最基本的目标之一是
to help you keep your customers'
帮助你来保证你用户的数据
data secure and private.
都是安全隐秘的
And we do this by giving you
我们通过给你最好的
best practice tools and
实践工具和技术
technologies to help achieve
来帮助你
that goal.
实现这一目标
However, you need to do some
然而
work yourself.
你仍需自己完成一些工作
And that means avoiding legacy
这意味着
or deprecated algorithms when at
要尽可能地
all possible.
避免过时的算法
And it also means continuing to
这同时也意味着
upgrade to modern TLS
要不断更新
configurations.
TLS 的配置
If you're a server owner,
如果
operator, again, that means
你是一个服务器拥有者
moving to 1.2 to make sure that
或者服务器运行人员
every app that is ATS compliant
意味着你要将版本升级到 1.2
can speak to you.
来确保ATS下的每一个 App 都是可用的
If you're an app developer,
如果你是一个 App 开发人员
again, that means minimizing or
这意味着
reducing the use of exceptions.
要尽可能少的使用例外情况
And if you're particularly
如果
adventurous, that means also
你敢于尝试新鲜事物
trying out TLS 1.3 to prime your
不防尝试一下 TLS 1.3
application and your network for
来使你的 App 和网络
the next exciting version of
对下一个版本的协议
this protocol.
做好准备
If you'd like any more
如果
information on any of the topics
针对我和 Bailey 所讨论到的问题
that Bailey and I discussed, you
你想获得更多的信息
can visit this link above.
你可以访问上面的链接
Next up in this room we have a
之后
session on privacy and your
我们将会有一个
apps, which I highly encourage
关于
everyone to attend, given your
隐私与 App 的讲解
interest in security.
非常推荐大家听一下
Tomorrow we have two back to
明天
back jam packed sessions full of
我们也会有一些
advances in networking, which
有关计算机网络发展的介绍
would be very interesting and
对于
relevant to anyone at all who is
对 TLS 有兴趣的人来说
interested in TLS.
会非常有趣
And that's all I have.
这就是我今天要讲的全部了
Thank you for your time and
谢谢大家的时间
attention, enjoy the rest of the
和出席
conference.
也希望大家能喜欢之后的会议内容